[{
    "id":"1",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "Atoms with the same atomic number but different masses (same number of protons, but different number of neutrons)",
    "back": "isotopes"
},

{
    "id":"2",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "Hybrid atomic orbitals that arise from the combination of one s orbital and two p orbitals",
    "back": "sp²"
},

{
    "id":"3",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "Hybrid atomic orbitals that arise from the combination of one s orbital and three p orbitals",
    "back": "sp³"
},

{
    "id":"4",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "Conceptually, combining atomic orbitals to obtain hybrid atomic orbitals in a way that facilitates the description of bonding within a molecule",
    "back": "hybridization"
},

{
    "id":"5",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "A bond formed by sideways overlap of atomic orbitals, resulting in electron density above and below a line between the two nuclei",
    "back": "pi bond (π bond)"
},

{
    "id":"6",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "A bond formed by end-on overlap of two atomic orbitals along a line between the two nuclei",
    "back": "sigma bond (σ bond)"
},

{
    "id":"6",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "Valence electrons that are not involved in bonding",
    "back": "lone pair (non-bonding electrons)"
},

{
    "id":"7",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "The tendency for main group elements, eg. C, N, O, to attain eight electrons in their valence shells",
    "back": "octet rule"
},

{
    "id":"8",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "Two atoms share a pair of electrons",
    "back": "covalent bond"
},

{
    "id":"9",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "Arrangement of four groups around a central atom, with maximum distance between them (~ 109.5° bond angles)",
    "back": "tetrahedral"
},

{
    "id":"10",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "A single, unchanging structure which can be represented by multiple resonance structures (forms)",
    "back": "resonance hybrid"
},

{
    "id":"11",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "Alternate structure diagrams for a molecule which can be interconverted by shifting only π and non-bonding valence electrons",
    "back": "resonance structures (resonance forms)"
},

{
    "id":"12",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "In a structure diagram, the charge associated with an atom which does not possess the appropriate number of valence electrons",
    "back": "formal charge"
},

{
    "id":"13",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "A characteristic group of atoms and/or bonds that have predictable chemical behaviors",
    "back": "functional group"
},

{
    "id":"14",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "A structure diagram that avoids explicitly showing carbon atoms and hydrogen atoms that are attached to carbon",
    "back": "line-bond structure (bond-line structure)"
},

{
    "id":"15",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "A structure diagram that shows no bonds, instead implying bonds by clustering atoms and groups of atoms together",
    "back": "condensed structure"
},

{
    "id":"16",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "A structure diagram that shows bonds as pairs of dots or lines between two atoms, and non-bonded (lone pair) electrons as pairs of dots",
    "back": "Lewis structure"
},

{
    "id":"17",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "Arrangement of two groups around a central atom, with maximum distance between them (~ 180° bond angles)",
    "back": "linear"
},

{
    "id":"18",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "Arrangement of three groups around a central atom, with maximum distance between them (~ 120° bond angles)",
    "back": "trigonal planar"
},

{
    "id":"19",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "Arrangement of four groups around a central atom, with maximum distance between them (~ 109.5° bond angles)",
    "back": "tetrahedral"
},

{
    "id":"20",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "Conceptually, combining atomic orbitals to obtain hybrid atomic orbitals in a way that facilitates the description of bonding within a molecule",
    "back": "hybridization"
},

{
    "id":"21",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "Hard and soft acids and bases",
    "back": "HSAB theory (Pearson acid-base theory)"
},

{
    "id":"22",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "An electron pair donor",
    "back": "Lewis base"
},

{
    "id":"23",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "An electron pair acceptor",
    "back": "Lewis acid"
},

{
    "id":"24",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "A species with separate positively and negatively charged groups",
    "back": "zwitterion"
},

{
    "id":"25",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "A negatively charged species",
    "back": "anion"
},

{
    "id":"26",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "Valence electrons that are not involved in bonding",
    "back": "lone pair (non-bonding electrons)"
},

{
    "id":"27",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "The tendency for main group elements, eg. C, N, O, to attain eight electrons in their valence shells",
    "back": "octet rule"
},

{
    "id":"28",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "Two atoms share a pair of electrons",
    "back": "covalent bond"
},

{
    "id":"29",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "A positively charged species",
    "back": "cation"
},

{
    "id":"30",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "A substance with a high pKa",
    "back": "weak acid"
},

{
    "id":"31",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "A substance with a low pKa",
    "back": "strong acid"
},

{
    "id":"32",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "The product formed when a base gains a proton",
    "back": "conjugate acid"
},

{
    "id":"33",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "The product formed when an acid loses a proton",
    "back": "conjugate base"
},

{
    "id":"34",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "A substance that accepts a proton (H+)",
    "back": "base"
},

{
    "id":"35",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "A substance that donates a proton (H+)",
    "back": "acid"
},

{
    "id":"36",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "A structure diagram that shows bonds as pairs of dots or lines between two atoms, and non-bonded (lone pair) electrons as pairs of dots",
    "back": "Lewis structure"
},

{
    "id":"37",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "Arrangement of two groups around a central atom, with maximum distance between them (~ 180° bond angles)",
    "back": "linear"
},

{
    "id":"38",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "Arrangement of three groups around a central atom, with maximum distance between them (~ 120° bond angles)",
    "back": "trigonal planar"
},

{
    "id":"39",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "Arrangement of four groups around a central atom, with maximum distance between them (~ 109.5° bond angles)",
    "back": "tetrahedral"
},

{
    "id":"40",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "A single, unchanging structure which can be represented by multiple resonance structures (forms)",
    "back": "resonance hybrid"
},

{
    "id":"41",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "Alternate structure diagrams for a molecule which can be interconverted by shifting only π and non-bonding valence electrons",
    "back": "resonance structures (resonance forms)"
},

{
    "id":"42",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "In a structure diagram, the charge associated with an atom which does not possess the appropriate number of valence electrons",
    "back": "formal charge"
},

{
    "id":"43",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "A characteristic group of atoms and/or bonds that have predictable chemical behaviors",
    "back": "functional group"
},

{
    "id":"44",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "A structure diagram that avoids explicitly showing carbon atoms and hydrogen atoms that are attached to carbon",
    "back": "line-bond structure (bond-line structure)"
},

{
    "id":"45",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "A structure diagram that shows no bonds, instead implying bonds by clustering atoms and groups of atoms together",
    "back": "condensed structure"
},

{
    "id":"46",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "A structure diagram that shows bonds as pairs of dots or lines between two atoms, and non-bonded (lone pair) electrons as pairs of dots",
    "back": "Lewis structure"
},

{
    "id":"47",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "Arrangement of two groups around a central atom, with maximum distance between them (~ 180° bond angles)",
    "back": "linear"
},

{
    "id":"48",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "Arrangement of three groups around a central atom, with maximum distance between them (~ 120° bond angles)",
    "back": "trigonal planar"
},

{
    "id":"49",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "Arrangement of four groups around a central atom, with maximum distance between them (~ 109.5° bond angles)",
    "back": "tetrahedral"
},
{
    "id":"50",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "a chemical reaction between an alcohol and an acid to produce an ester and water",
    "back": "esterification"
},

{
    "id":"51",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "an organic compound containing both the amine group (-NH2) and the carboxyl group (-COOH)",
    "back": "amino acid"
},

{
    "id":"52",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "an ammonia derivative in which one or more of the hydrogen atoms are replaced by an alkyl group",
    "back": "amine"
},

{
    "id":"53",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "the product obtained from the reaction of an organic acid with an amine",
    "back": "amide"
},

{
    "id":"54",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "one of a homologous series of hydrocarbons that contain one triple covalent bond",
    "back": "alkyne"
},

{
    "id":"55",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "one of a homologous series of hydrocarbons that contain one double covalent bond",
    "back": "alkene"
},

{
    "id":"56",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "one of a homologous series of saturated hydrocarbons (CnH2n+2)",
    "back": "alkane"
},

{
    "id":"57",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "an organic compound in which the carbonyl group (-C=O) is at the end of a carbon chain",
    "back": "aldehyde"
},

{
    "id":"58",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "an organic compound containing the hydroxyl group (-OH) as the functional group",
    "back": "alcohol"
},

{
    "id":"59",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "an organic reaction in which a substance such as hydrogen or a halogen is added to the site of a double or triple bond in an organic molecule",
    "back": "addition reaction"
},

{
    "id":"60",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "A substance with a high pKa",
    "back": "weak acid"
},

{
    "id":"61",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "A substance with a low pKa",
    "back": "strong acid"
},

{
    "id":"62",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "The product formed when a base gains a proton",
    "back": "conjugate acid"
},

{
    "id":"63",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "The product formed when an acid loses a proton",
    "back": "conjugate base"
},

{
    "id":"64",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "A substance that accepts a proton (H+)",
    "back": "base"
},

{
    "id":"65",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "A substance that donates a proton (H+)",
    "back": "acid"
},

{
    "id":"66",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "A structure diagram that shows bonds as pairs of dots or lines between two atoms, and non-bonded (lone pair) electrons as pairs of dots",
    "back": "Lewis structure"
},

{
    "id":"67",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "Arrangement of two groups around a central atom, with maximum distance between them (~ 180° bond angles)",
    "back": "linear"
},

{
    "id":"68",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "Arrangement of three groups around a central atom, with maximum distance between them (~ 120° bond angles)",
    "back": "trigonal planar"
},

{
    "id":"69",
    "type":"1",
    "front": "Arrangement of four groups around a central atom, with maximum distance between them (~ 109.5° bond angles)",
    "back": "tetrahedral"
},

{
    "id":"70",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Strontium phosphate",
    "back": "Sr₃(PO₄)₂"
},

{
    "id":"71",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Carbon monoxide",
    "back": "CO"
},

{
    "id":"72",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Copper (I) hydroxide",
    "back": "CuOH"
},

{
    "id":"73",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Magnesium phosphide",
    "back": "Mg₃P₂"
},

{
    "id":"74",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Copper (II) nitrite",
    "back": "Cu(NO₂)₂"
},

{
    "id":"75",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Lithium hydride",
    "back": "LiH"
},

{
    "id":"76",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Nitric Acid",
    "back": "HNO₃"
},

{
    "id":"77",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Beryllium sulfide",
    "back": "BeS"
},

{
    "id":"78",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Potassium permanganate",
    "back": "KMnO₄"
},

{
    "id":"79",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Potassium dichromate",
    "back": "K₂Cr₂O₇"
},

{
    "id":"80",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Iron (III) hydroxide",
    "back": "Fe(OH)₃"
},

{
    "id":"81",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Lead (IV) oxide",
    "back": "PbO₂"
},

{
    "id":"82",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Carbon dioxide",
    "back": "CO₂"
},

{
    "id":"83",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Tin (IV) bromide",
    "back": "SnBr₄"
},

{
    "id":"84",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Aluminum oxide",
    "back": "Al₂O₃"
},

{
    "id":"85",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Silver nitrate",
    "back": "AgNO₃"
},

{
    "id":"86",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Carbon tetrachloride",
    "back": "CCl₄"
},

{
    "id":"87",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Sodium cyanide",
    "back": "NaCN"
},

{
    "id":"88",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Copper (II) sulfide",
    "back": "CuS"
},

{
    "id":"89",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Iodic Acid",
    "back": "HIO₃"
},

{
    "id":"90",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Zinc chloride",
    "back": "ZnCl₂"
},

{
    "id":"91",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Hydrofluoric Acid",
    "back": "HF"
},

{
    "id":"92",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Barium sulfide",
    "back": "BaS"
},

{
    "id":"93",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Ammonium chromate",
    "back": "(NH₄)₂CrO₄"
},

{
    "id":"94",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Mercury (I) oxide",
    "back": "Hg₂O"
},

{
    "id":"95",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Calcium bicarbonate",
    "back": "Ca(HCO₃)₂"
},

{
    "id":"96",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Iron (II) oxide",
    "back": "FeO"
},

{
    "id":"97",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Ammonium Nitrate",
    "back": "NH₄NO₃"
},

{
    "id":"98",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Manganese (IV) oxide",
    "back": "MnO₂"
},

{
    "id":"99",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Hydroiodic Acid",
    "back": "HI"
},

{
    "id":"100",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Silver nitrate",
    "back": "AgNO₃"
},

{
    "id":"101",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Phosphoric Acid",
    "back": "H₃PO₄"
},

{
    "id":"102",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Copper (I) oxide",
    "back": "Cu₂O"
},

{
    "id":"103",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Sulfur dioxide",
    "back": "SO₂"
},

{
    "id":"104",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Aluminum hypochlorate",
    "back": "Al(ClO)₃"
},

{
    "id":"105",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Magnesium sulfide",
    "back": "MgS"
},

{
    "id":"106",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Cobalt bisulfate",
    "back": "Co(HSO₄)₂"
},

{
    "id":"107",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Aluminum oxide",
    "back": "Al₂O₃"
},

{
    "id":"108",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Silver nitrate",
    "back": "AgNO₃"
},

{
    "id":"109",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Carbon tetrachloride",
    "back": "CCl₄"
},

{
    "id":"110",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Carbon tetrachloride",
    "back": "CCl₄"
},

{
    "id":"111",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Sodium cyanide",
    "back": "NaCN"
},

{
    "id":"112",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Copper (II) sulfide",
    "back": "CuS"
},

{
    "id":"113",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Iodic Acid",
    "back": "HIO₃"
},

{
    "id":"114",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Zinc chloride",
    "back": "ZnCl₂"
},

{
    "id":"115",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Hydrofluoric Acid",
    "back": "HF"
},

{
    "id":"116",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Barium sulfide",
    "back": "BaS"
},

{
    "id":"117",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Ammonium chromate",
    "back": "(NH₄)₂CrO₄"
},

{
    "id":"118",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Mercury (I) oxide",
    "back": "Hg₂O"
},

{
    "id":"119",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Sodium oxalate",
    "back": "Na₂C₂O₄"
},

{
    "id":"120",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Nitrogen dioxide",
    "back": "NO₂"
},

{
    "id":"121",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Phosphoric Acid",
    "back": "H₃PO₄"
},

{
    "id":"122",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Copper (I) oxide",
    "back": "Cu₂O"
},

{
    "id":"123",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Sulfur dioxide",
    "back": "SO₂"
},

{
    "id":"124",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Aluminum hypochlorate",
    "back": "Al(ClO)₃"
},

{
    "id":"125",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Magnesium sulfide",
    "back": "MgS"
},

{
    "id":"126",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Cobalt bisulfate",
    "back": "Co(HSO₄)₂"
},

{
    "id":"127",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Aluminum oxide",
    "back": "Al₂O₃"
},

{
    "id":"128",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Silver nitrate",
    "back": "AgNO₃"
},

{
    "id":"129",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Carbon tetrachloride",
    "back": "CCl₄"
},

{
    "id":"130",
    "type":"2",
    "front": "Sulfur dioxide",
    "back": "SO₂"
}]